The ballad of a true original.
A Complete Unknown is a drama, music film directed by James Mangold.
New York, early 1960s.
Against the backdrop of a vibrant music scene and tumultuous cultural upheaval, an enigmatic 19-year-old from Minnesota arrives
in the West Village with his guitar and revolutionary talent, destined to change the course of American music.
Bob Dylan, played by Timothée Chalamet.
Pete Seeger, played by Edward Norton.
Sylvie Russo, played by Elle Fanning.
Joan Baez, played by Monica Barbaro.
Woody Guthrie, played by Scoot McNairy.
Albert Grossman, played by Dan Fogler.
A Complete Unknown is a 2024 American biographical film about the early career of American singer-songwriter Bob Dylan,
directed by James Mangold, written by Mangold and Jay Cocks, and loosely based on the 2015 book Dylan Goes Electric!
by Elijah Wald.
A Complete Unknown examines the period of 1961–1965, beginning with Dylan's start as an American folk singer,
and ending with his controversial use of electric instruments at the 1965 Newport Folk Festival.
Dylan is portrayed by Timothée Chalamet, who also produced the film.
Edward Norton, Elle Fanning, Monica Barbaro, Boyd Holbrook, Dan Fogler, Norbert Leo Butz, Eriko
Hatsune, Big Bill Morganfield, Will Harrison, and Scoot McNairy appear in supporting roles.
A Complete Unknown premiered at the Dolby Theatre in Los Angeles on December 10, 2024, and
was released in the United States by Searchlight Pictures on December 25.
It grossed $140.5 million worldwide and received generally positive reviews.
It was named one of the top 10 films of 2024 by the American
Film Institute and the National Board of Review.
The National Board of Review also awarded Fanning Best Supporting Actress.
The film earned eight nominations at the 97th Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best Director, Best
Actor (Chalamet), Best Supporting Actor (Norton), and Best Supporting Actress (Barbaro).
It received three nominations at the 82nd Golden Globe Awards (including Best Motion Picture – Drama), four at the 31st Screen
Actors Guild Awards (winning Best Actor for Chalamet), and six at the British Academy Film Awards (including Best Film).
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
musician, biography, 1960s, disdainful.
The tone is emotional.